### **GIRISH KUMAR KANNAN**

girishkumar.kannan@gmail.com (407) 633-8501

https://www.linkedin.com/in/girish-kumar-kannan https://www.github.com/GirishKumarK 1050 7th Street #2, Miami Beach, Florida, 33139.

#### **SUMMARY**

An M.S.Cp.E graduate with 3 years of professional computer engineering experience and a wide range of technical skills in the field of Machine Learning, Data Science and Automation. Excels at Python Programming, Data Processing / Analysis / Visualization. Critical thinker and a problem solver. Pays great attention to details. Versatile and hardworking, passionate towards contributing to a team to accelerate outcomes and goals. Takes personal responsibility and accountable to assigned tasks. Motivated towards developing and deploying quality technologies, systems and processes.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Roboticist / Robotics Engineer, Quartile 3 Robotics, Miami Beach, Florida, USA.

Nov 2018 – Present

- Developed a program that will help take Restaurant orders using Speech Synthesis and Facial Recognition in Python. Automated data interaction and exchange between local and a cloud database server.
- Designed & developed GUIs using Python to actuate a Humanoid Robot by a Remote User, controlled through intranet & internet. Generated APIs to handle quality data-flow between the robot and the user through an online cloud SQL database.
- Developed API that can interact with SQL databases using Python to interface a GPS RTK device. Decoded, interpreted and reformatted incoming binary data. Transformed the data for exporting to a database.

# Computer Engineer Intern, Parsound LLC, Orlando, Florida, USA.

Aug 2018 – Jan 2019

- Designed and developed advanced DSP algorithms, signal communication strategy and device communication topologies.
- Collaborated across disciplines to make user-friendly amplifier control systems, effectively automating smart soundscapes.
- Developed a program in Python to handle automatic data exchange between a software and a data file. Collected, reorganized, transformed and exported the data file to be imported directly into the software. Handled data errors and corrections.
- Lead engineering teams of up to 10 people, conducted interviews and made important decisions.

## DSP Engineer (Volunteer-Associate), Parseval LLC, Orlando, Florida, USA.

May 2017 – April 2018

- Developed a project that saves trapped lives in a vehicle endangered by unsafe temperatures. Designed electronic circuit boards and programmed the devices using Python and C/C++.
- Designed and programmed automated microphone stand to perceive soundscape of a room using Matlab and C/C++.
- Built, maintained and patched computers and cables, installed and fixed operating systems & set up complex development environments to support development team.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Operating Systems: Windows (10+ years), Linux (3+ years Ubuntu, Raspbian, Debian distros.)
- Programming Languages: Python (NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, MatPlotLib, Seaborn), MATLAB, C, C++, SQL, [R, Java, HTML]
- Applications: Microsoft Office Suite / 365, Libre Office Suite

## **EDUCATION**

University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida, USA.

August 2016 - May 2018

### **Master of Science in Computer Engineering**

CGPA: 3.5 / 4.0

Related Coursework: Advanced A.I., Machine Learning, Intelligent Systems, Computer Vision, Signal Processing.

#### **Related Projects:**

- Occupancy Grid-based 2D-SLAM Robot: Deployed A-Star Search and Reinforcement Learning techniques to navigate a robot that can Simultaneously Localize and Map a quasi-stochastic region using Occupancy Grid model using Python, C/C++ and Matlab.
- Multi-Detection Computer Vision: Developed a set of Computer Vision algorithms to make a webcam detect hand gestures as mouse commands and perform Optical Character Recognition as well, on a real-time basis using Python.
- Programmed and compared Machine Learning algorithms to datasets to understand the efficiency of every algorithm performed profiling, extraction, pruning, transformation and visualization with Python libraries on every dataset used to produce results.
- Designed and demonstrated various Signal Filtering and Processing techniques to analyze the efficiency of each design observed incoming data, smoothed and corrected defects and generated statistics on the incoming data stream.

**SRM University**, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.

August 2011 – May 2015

CGPA: 8.9 / 10.0

### **Bachelor of Technology in Mechatronics**

#### Related Projects:

- Autonomous Robot Swarm for Goal Searching: Designed an Arduino-based three-agent swarm that uses Alpha-Beta Coordination Algorithm using C/C++ for Goal Searching and Convergence for applications like search and rescue and resource foraging.
- Gesture Controlled Mouse: Designed an Arduino-based Wireless Gesture-controlled Mouse using Digital IMU to aid people with limb-disabilities. Built and programmed an interface that translated hand gestures to cursor actions on a computer using C/C++.